## Alex Laties

387 Franklin Avenue, Apt 103 Brooklyn, NY 11238 Phone: 267 825 2530

Website: http://alex.laties.info/ E-Mail: alex@laties.info

## General Purpose Software Developer

Alex Laties  $^{^{\text{TM}}}$  is a general purpose programmer that has worked on building, maintaining, and scaling web applications. He primarily works in Python, but has no strong language preference and has demonstrated some faculty with C, C#, Java, Ruby, PHP, and Javascript. He has worked in larger IDEs, such as Visual Studio, MonoDevelop, and XCode, but claims no great proficiencies in any of them. He primarily uses some hodge podge of Vim and assorted plugins as an IDE.

Alex has worked with teams in an agile style to quickly deliver features and products. He has worked with ticketing systems, such as Jira and Trello, to manage work loads. He has worked with source control systems, like Subversion and Git, to prevent himself and teammates from going crazy. He has worked in a test driven style and found it rather nice.

Alex has contributed some code to open source projects Bottle and pyrollbar.

Work	History

	)		
			• Worked with Django 1.3 on Python 2.7 to maintain a web application and mobile API.
			• Built prototypes for internal CRMs.
			• Built a new mobile API stack in Bottle.
March 2012 - October 2013	Voxy, Inc	Software Engineer	• Set up loadbalancing for web and mobile stacks using haproxy and pacemaker.
			• Set up and wrote initial recipes for Chef provisioning service.
			<ul> <li>Also dealt with PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Varnish, Celery, Redis, uwsgi, gunicorn, and nginx.</li> </ul>
Fall/Winter 2010 - January 2011	UPenn School of Medicine	Lab Assistant	Assisted in the generation, collection, and processing of data from experiments.  Dealt with Matlab, Excel, and Python, as well as a variety of lab equipment.
Education			
Fall 2007 - Spring 2010	UPenn School of Engineerin	ng	Majored in Computer Science. Learned some theory, implemented a CPU, an OS shell, and some sweet buffer overflows. Also a little Chinese. Dropped out due to health reasons.
Fall 1993 - Spring 2007	Chestnut Hill Acade	emy	Standard education from kindergarten through high school. Learned some Java and build a 3D solarium.
Of Note			
February 18, 2012	Hacker Olympics	2nd in Individual and 3rd in Team	Awesome. Best hackathon ever. Consisted of small, silly algorithmic and social engineering challenges.
April 20-21, 2010	HackNY	2nd (3rd really)	Great. Built beatmon, a social media traffic surge detector and resource swapper for low bandwidth sites, in python with the help of Raymond Ko.
January 2010	PennApps	Did not place	Was a lot of fun. Worked on the Android mobile client for MobLaundry, a washer/dryer status API, as well as the HTML scraper (ugh) to pull data in for the API.